unco.edu 2019-06-15

# University Website Privacy Statement

The University of Northern Colorado recognizes the importance of protection of individual privacy and takes various steps to protect, or limit access to so-called “personally identifiable information” (“PII”) provided by our website visitors. Collection of non-PII may occur automatically when you visit the University’s website.  It is your choice whether or not to provide PII to the University via the Internet.  If you choose not to do so, you can still visit most of the University’s websites but you may be unable to access certain options and services available through those websites.  Information collection methods utilized by access to the University’s website include: 

## Web visit logs and cookies

Certain information is collected automatically when you visit the University’s website.  This information includes IP address (number assigned to a computer for accessing the Internet), type of browser, Internet Service Provider, pages visited, time spent on the site, date and time of the visit and country from which you access the website. This information is collected to allow us to understand the needs of users and to analyze structure of the University’s website. 

Cookies are small pieces of data placed on a user’s browser and are used to keep track of settings or data for a particular website. You may turn them off through your browser or set your browser to notify you before accepting them. The University websites use cookies to store information necessary to provide a service or access into a website. Persistent cookies are tracking cookies used for remarketing purposes that may allow other third party vendors to serve advertising to you when you visit their websites based on the cookies placed on your system as a result of your access of the University’s website. These cookies may also be turned off through settings you make on your browser or through settings that are provided by Google Display Advertising, Facebook Advertising and other similar companies.Users can opt out of third-party advertising cookies from many advertising services, including Google, by visiting the [Network Advertising Initiative's Opt-Out page](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp). 

## Network traffic logs

In the process of ensuring network security and optimum performance, the University may collect email headers and addresses. 

## Consent to disclosure of personally identifiable information

By providing PII voluntarily when you visit the University website, you have consented to the collection and disclosure of PII for the purpose indicated. For example, the information may be used by the appropriate University employee to contact you or provide requested service. 

The University may provide information to service providers or agents of the University to enable them to carry out their assigned functions or provide a service to you but the will take reasonable and appropriate steps to protect that information from unauthorized access or disclosure by those providers or agents. 

If personal information is requested on the website or is volunteered by you as a user of the website, state and federal law may protect that information. However, all information becomes a public record once it is provided and may be subject to public inspection and copying under the Colorado Open Records Act if not otherwise protected by federal or state law.  
The University may collect or disclose PII without your consent if disclosure is: 

  * Necessary to perform the University’s statutory duties;
  * Allowed by and consistent with the provisions of federal or state law;
  * Required by a court order;
  * Necessary to protect the safety of the University community, University visitors or similarly situated individuals; and/or 
  * Necessary to enforce the rights of the University to prevent attempted or actual unauthorized access to its information technology assets. 

You are cautioned that the collection of PII provided by anyone on your behalf will be treated the same as if such information was provided by you and may be subject to public access. 

## Security

Notwithstanding security measures that the University undertakes, the University does not represent or warrant that PII will be protected against unauthorized access or misuse. 

## Other web links

The University website also provides links to web pages outside of the University domain.  The University is not responsible for the privacy practices or content of any of those websites. 

## Revisions to this Privacy Statement

The University may revise this Privacy Statement at any time by posting such changes on the University website. Your use of the University’s website constitutes acceptance of this Privacy Statement and any revision made to it. 

## Contact information

If you have any questions regarding this Privacy Statement, please contact:

Daniel R. Satriana, Jr.  
General Counsel  
Carter Hall 4000 Campus Box 29   
Greeley, Colorado 80639   
Fax (970) 351-1110  
Contact (970) 351-1152
